Guide to the Washington Square Journal RG.39.187
New York University Archives
Washington Square Journal
1955-1973
New York University Archives
RG.39.187
13.25 Linear Feet In 9 flat boxes and 12 reels of microfilm
This collection contains issues from the student newspaper the Square Journal, later known as the Washington Square Journal, dating from 1955 to 1973. This newspaper documented student life at NYU (particuarly at the Washington Square campus), local and national news, campus living, and student clubs. The collection is extensive but not comprehensive, there may be some issues that were published but are not included in this collection. This collections includes issues in their original print format as well as microfilmed copies.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Arrangement
Newspapers are arranged chronologically.
Biographical / Historical
New York University has had many student newspapers since its founding. The University Heights campus and the Washington Square campus had separate student newspapers until 1973 when the University Heights campus was closed. The Washington Square Journal was preceded by the Washington Square Bulletin and succeeded by the Washington Square Daily News.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains issues of student newspapers the Square Journal and Washington Square Journal dating from 1955-1973. The newspaper was printed daily and documented student life, university news, and local or international news with relevancy to NYU.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Researchers must consult microfilm copies due to the fragility of the original newspapers.
College student newspapers and periodicals.; Student activities.
- Microfilm Copies
  - Washington Square Journal, September 1955-May 1958 (Box Microfilm 6, Reel 5050)
  - Washington Square Journal, September 1958-May 1961 (Box Microfilm 6, Reel 5051)
  - Washington Square Journal, December 1961-May 1962, September 1966-May 1967 (Box Microfilm 6, Reel 5052)
  - Washington Square Journal, 1962-1964 (Box Microfilm 3, Reel 1)
  - Washington Square Journal, 1964-1966 (Box Microfilm 3, Reel 2)
  - Washington Square Journal, 1966-1968 (Box Microfilm 3, Reel 3)
  - Washington Square Journal, September 1967-May 1969 (Box Microfilm 6, Reel 5053)
  - Washington Square Journal, 1968-1970 (Box Microfilm 3, Reel 4)
  - Washington Square Journal, 1969-1971 (Box Microfilm 3, Reel 5)
  - Washington Square Journal, September 1969-May 1970 (Box Microfilm 6, Reel 5054)
  - Washington Square Journal, September 1970-May 1973 (Box Microfilm 3, Reel 5055)
  - Washington Square Journal, September 1970-May 1973 (Box Microfilm 6, Reel 5055)
  - Washington Square Journal, 1971-1973 (Box Microfilm 3, Reel 6)
- Print Copies (restricted due to preservation concerns)
  - Washington Square Journal, September 27, 1955-May 6, 1957 (Box 1)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Original copies are very fragile. Researchers must consult microfilm for these issues.
  - Washington Square Journal, November 19, 1957-February 26, 1959 (Box 2)
  - Washington Square Journal, December 9, 1959-May 10, 1961 (Box 3)
  - Washington Square Journal, April 30, 1962-May 1966 (Box 4)
  - Washington Square Journal, December 10, 1966-September 25, 1967 (Box 5)
  - Washington Square Journal, September 19, 1968-May 15, 1969 (Box 6)
  - Washington Square Journal, September 18, 1969-May 18, 1970 (Box 7)
  - Washington Square Journal, September 17, 1970-May 11, 1972 (Box 8)
  - Washington Square Journal, October 2, 1972-May 17, 1973 (Box 9)